Madhavan V

Full Stack Developer MERN

I am a dedicated developer with a B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering. After three years in a non-IT role, I decided to pivot my Career into software development, completing the MERN Full Stack Development course at Guvi Geek Networks. With skills in MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js, I am eager to contribute to impactful projects and grow as a versatile developer.

★ 13isid4me@gmail.com

Kovilpatti, India

in linkedin.com/in/Madhavan@96

instagram.com/memer_maddy

9994576279

madhavanportfolio.netlify.app/

github.com/MadhavanV96

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering -Computer Sciences and Engineering

Rrase College of Engineering, Chennai

08/2014 - 04/2018 7.4/10

WORK EXPERIENCE (NON IT)

System Engineer Shrikarra Vidhya Mandhir

07/2019 - 04/2021 Kovilpatti

Senior Secondary School(CBSE Curriculum).

Responsibilities

- Administered and maintained the school's IT infrastructure, including 30+ computers, local networks, and ERP systems, ensuring seamless operations.
- Designed and developed visually appealing marketing materials, including posters and brochures, to promote school activities and events.
- Streamlined technical support processes by implementing efficient troubleshooting protocols that eliminated the three primary causes of system crashes, leading to enhanced overall user experience in daily operations.

Cable TV Operator Royal TV Pvt. Ltd.

07/2018 - 07/2019

Rajapalayam

Local Cable TV Channel Responsibilities

- Chief Programmer of the channel. Scheduling Ads and Programmes.
- Designing Banners.

IT Faculty M.M. Vidyashram

05/2023 - 08/2024 Kovilpatti

Senior Secondary School (CBSE Curriculum)

Responsibilities

- Administered and maintained the school's IT infrastructure, including 30+ computers, local networks, and ERP systems, ensuring seamless operations.
- Designed and developed visually appealing marketing materials, including posters and brochures, to promote school activities and events.
- Captured high-quality photographs and videos for documentation and promotional purposes during school events.

SKILLS

React.js HTML5

CSS3 Node.js

JavaScript (ES6+) Tailwind CSS

Express.js MongoDB

mongoose RESTful APIs

Postman Render

Netlify npm

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator

MS Office

PROJECTS

Flight Booking and Reservation System using Amadeus API - FSD Project (12/2024 - 12/2024)

✓

- Description: Completed a real-time flight booking and reservation system integrating the Amadeus API for flight data and Razorpay for secure payment processing. It was the final capstone project assigned and validated by GUVI Geek Networks Pvt. Ltd.
- Frontend: ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, Database: MongoDB, Other Technologies: Amadeus API, Razorpay for Payment
- Deploy URL: https://bookyourticketguvi.netlify.app/, Github Repo: https://github.com/MadhavanV96/Real-Time-Flight-Booking-System-Using-Amadeus-API--Front-END.git

Password Reset Flow [MERN] (11/2024 - 11/2024)

 Description: The task is to implement a correct password reset flow with email verification and proper update of the new password in the database for the web app using MERN Stack.

Portfolio Project [React Project] (10/2024 - 10/2024)

✓

URL: https://madhavanportfolio.netlify.app/

CERTIFICATES

Full Stack Developer- MERN (08/2024 - Present)

I am a certified Full Stack Developer in MERN Stack by HCL Guvi Geek Networks Pvt. Ltd.

Odoo Project (01/2018 - 04/2018)

Final Year Project certified by C-DAC, Chennai